In this video, we're going to get a better understanding
このビデオでは、より深く理解していきましょう
of what a coding assistant is. Yes,
コーディングアシスタントとは何かについてです。はい、
a coding assistant is a tool that writes code, but I want
コーディングアシスタントはコードを書くツールですが、私は皆さんに
to give you a deeper understanding of what's going on behind the scenes.
舞台裏で何が起こっているのかをより深く理解していただきたいです。
You see, by understanding what a coding assistant really
コーディングアシスタントが実際に何をして、
does and how it works, you'll have a greater appreciation
どのように機能するかを理解することで、
of what makes a truly amazing assistant to
チームを補完する、真に素晴らしいアシスタントが
complement your team. Here's one way that you
何であるかをより高く評価できるようになります。
can picture what a coding assistant is doing. An assistant
コーディングアシスタントが何をしているかを理解する
is first given a task. In this case, maybe the assistant
一つの方法を説明します。アシスタントはまずタスクを与えられます。
needs to fix a bug based upon some kind of error message.
この場合、アシスタントはエラーメッセージに基づいてバグを修正する必要があるかもしれません。
This task is passed off internally to a language model, which
このタスクは内部的に言語モデルに渡され、
needs to figure out how to solve the issue. Now, different
言語モデルは問題を解決する方法を見つけ出す必要があります。
language models solve problems in very different styles depending
異なる言語モデルは、タスクの複雑さに応じて
upon the complexity of the task. But in many cases, they
非常に異なるスタイルで問題を解決します。
work very much like how a human would work. It
しかし、多くの場合、それらは人間が作業するのと
first might need to gather context by understanding what the error
非常に似た方法で機能します。まず、エラーが
is referring to, what area in the code base is throwing the error,
何を参照しているのか、どのコードベースの領域がエラーを発生させているのか、
and what files seem to be relevant. Once
そしてどのファイルが関連しているように見えるのかを理解してコンテキストを収集する必要があるかもしれません。
it has gathered that information, it then needs to formulate a
その情報を収集したら、タスクをどのように実行するかを計画する必要があります。
plan on how it will actually accomplish the task.
この場合、コードを変更してテストを実行するか、
In this case, it might decide to change some code and then run
問題が実際に修正されたことを確認するためのテストを作成することを決定するかもしれません。
or write a test to verify that the issue is actually
最終的に、アクションを実行します。
fixed. Finally, it will take an action. In
この場合、ファイルを作成してテストを実行することになるかもしれません。
this case, that might be updating a file and running
さて、このプロセス全体について、さらに情報を共有したいと思います。
the test. Now, I want to give you some more information
特に、ここでの最初と最後のステップは、
on this entire process. In particular, I'd
コーディングアシスタントが実際に何かを行う必要があることに注意してください。
like you to notice that the first and last steps here
つまり、外部世界から情報を収集したり、
require the coding assistant to actually do something.
何らかの方法で外部世界に影響を与えたりすることです。
In other words, to actually gather information from the outside world
例えば、コンテキストを収集するために、アシスタントはファイルを読み取ったり、
or affect the outside world in some way. For
オンラインでドキュメントを取得したりする必要があるかもしれません。
example, to gather context, the assistant needs to maybe
そしてアクションを実行するためには、アシスタントは実際にコマンドを実行したり、
read a file or fetch some documentation online.
ファイルを編集したりする必要があるかもしれません。
And for taking an action, the assistant might need to actually
さて、言語モデルにこれらのことを実際に実行させることは、
run a command or edit a file. Now
実際に聞こえるよりも少し難しいです。
having a language model actually do these things
なぜそうなのかを理解するのを手伝いましょう。
is a little bit trickier than it actually sounds.
言語モデルと直接やり取りしていると想像してみましょう。
Let me help you understand why that is. Let's
つまり、それはコーディングアシスタント内で実行されているわけではありません。
imagine that we are interacting with a language model directly,
そして、この言語モデルに直接、main.goファイル内に
so it's not running inside of any coding assistant or anything
どのようなコードが書かれているか尋ねていると想像してみましょう。
like that. Let's then imagine that we asked this
コーディングアシスタントや同様のツールのコンテキスト外で実行されている
language model directly what code is written inside
言語モデルは、本質的にファイルを読み取ったり、
the main.go file. Language
コマンドを実行したりする能力を持っていません。
models running outside the context of any coding
言語モデルはテキストのようなコンテンツを取り込み、
assistant or similar tool do not inherently
テキストを返します。それだけです。それが機能の全てです。
have the ability to say read a file or write
これはすべての言語モデルに当てはまります。
a command or anything like that. Language
ですから、ファイルを読み取るように頼んでテキストをプレーンな言語モデルに送信した場合、
models take in content like text and they return
それはおそらく、ファイルを読み取る能力がないと答えるでしょう。
text. That's it. That's the entire extent
では、コーディングアシスタントや多くの、多くの他のツールが、
of their capabilities. And this is true of all language
言語モデルにファイルを「読み取らせる」ために何をしているのか見てみましょう。
models. So if you were to send some text
さて、何が起こるかというと、コーディングアシスタントに
into a plain language model asking to read a file,
リクエストを送信すると、コーディングアシスタントは
it would most likely respond by saying that it doesn't have
バックグラウンドであなたのリクエストに多くのテキストを自動的に追加します。
the ability to read any files. So let me show
この場合、コーディングアシスタントは、もしあなたが、
you what coding assistance and many, many other tools
言語モデル、ファイルを読み取りたいなら、非常に注意深くフォーマットされたメッセージで応答してください、
out there do to actually allow a language model to,
のようなテキストを追加すると想像できます。
quote unquote, read a file. So here's what happens. Whenever
例えば、ファイル読み取り：そして読み取るファイル名、のようなものです。
you send a request off to your coding assistant, the coding
この場合、言語モデルは、私たちの質問に答えるために
assistant behind the scenes is going to automatically append
そのファイルを読み取ることで応答する必要があることに気付くでしょう。
a lot of text into your request.
したがって、ファイル読み取り：main.goと応答するかもしれません。
In this particular case, we can imagine that the coding assistant
そして、コーディングアシスタントは、この非常に注意深くフォーマットされたメッセージを受け取り、
is going to add on some text that says something like, if you,
言語モデルがファイルを読み取ることで何らかのアクションを実行したいと考えていることを認識する責任を負います。
language model, want to read a file, respond with
したがって、コーディングアシスタントは実際にファイルを読み取り、
this very carefully formatted message. For
そのファイルのコンテンツを言語モデルに送信する責任を負います。
example, maybe something like, read file, colon,
言語モデルがそのファイルの実際のコンテンツを受け取ったので、
and then the name of a file to read. So in this
最終的な応答を作成して私たちに送信できます。
case, the language model would hopefully realize that in order
その応答の中で、私はこのファイルを読み取り、
to answer our question, it needs to respond
それにはある程度のコードが含まれています、ファイルの中身は何でも、
by reading that file. So it might respond with, read
と述べるかもしれません。
file colon main.go. Now the coding
言語モデルにこれらの追加の指示を与える
assistant would be in charge of receiving this very carefully
このシステム全体は、非常にうまくフォーマットされたり、注意深くフォーマットされた方法で応答するように
formatted message and realizing that the language model wants
依頼するのですが、ツール使用と呼ばれています。
to take some kind of action by reading a file. So
したがって、ツールはモデルに余分な機能を与えるために使用されます。
the coding assistant would then be responsible for actually a read
モデルは非常に特定の方法で応答する責任があります。
in the file and sending the contents of that file
そして、私たちのコーディングアシスタントのようなものは、実際に約束されたことを実行する責任があります。
back into the language model. Now that the language
つまり、実際にファイルを読み取ったり、ファイルを書き込んだり、
model has received the actual contents of that file, it
その他何でも。
can write a final response that gets sent back to us.
繰り返しになりますが、これは、
in which it might say, well, I read this file and it
現存するすべての言語モデルがどのように機能するかです。
contains some amount of code, whatever else, whatever's inside
それらはすべてツール使用という考え方で機能します。
that file. This entire system of giving
さて、理解すべき重要な点があります。
a language model these extra little instructions
Claudeシリーズのモデル、つまりOpus、Sonnet、Haikuは、
asking it to respond in a very well formatted or carefully
特にツールの機能、呼び出されるタイミング、
formatted way is referred to as tool use.
そしてそれらを使用して効果的にタスクを完了すること、
So tools are used to give models extra capabilities.
そしてそれらを非常に興味深い組み合わせで使用して、より高度または複雑なタスクを完了することを理解することに優れています。
The model is responsible for responding in a very particular
Claudeの強力なツール使用は、Claude Codeの
way. And then something like our coding assistant would be responsible
コーディングアシスタントとしての絶対的なコアとなる強みです。
for actually doing whatever was promised. So
その理由は次のとおりです。
actually reading a file, writing a file, or whatever else.
まず、述べたように、より優れたツール使用により、
Again, this is how every single language model out
Claudeはより複雑なタスクを処理できます。
there works. They all work with this idea of tool use.
第二に、Claude Code自体は拡張可能なので、
Now, here's the critical part to understand. The Claude series
新しいツールをClaudeに追加するのは非常に簡単です。
of models, so Opus, Sonnet, and Haiku,
そしてClaudeはそれらのツールを喜んで使用します。
are particularly strong at understanding what
これは、開発の世界で見られる急速な変化を考えると、
tools do, when they're called, and actually using
継続的な関連性にとって特に重要です。
them to effectively complete tasks and using them
つまり、Claude Codeは、今後数年間で
in really interesting combinations to complete
あなたと共に変化していくアシスタントです。
more advanced or complex tasks.
そして最後に、ツール使用の改善により、
Claude's strong tool use is the absolute core strength
インデックス作成に依存せず、
of Claude code as a coding assistant. Here's why.
コードベース全体を外部サーバーに送信することが多い
First, as I just mentioned, with better tool use,
インデックス作成に依存せずに、関連コードを見つけるために
Claude can handle more complex tasks.
コードベースを効果的に検索できるため、
Second, Claude code itself is extensible, so
セキュリティが向上することがよくあります。
it's really easy to add in new tools to Claude. And
このビデオで学んだことの簡単なレビューをしましょう。
Claude will happily make use of those tools.
コーディングアシスタントとは何かについてです。覚えておいてください、
This is especially important for continued relevance,
コーディングアシスタントは、内部的に言語モデルを使用して
given the fast changes that we're seeing in the world of development.
さまざまなタスクを完了します。これらの言語モデルは、
In other words, Claude Code is an assistant that
ツールを使用してタスクを実行する方法を知る必要があります。
will change with you in the years to come. And
与えられるタスクの大部分では、ツールはファイルを読み取ったり、
finally, with improved tool use, you often get better
ファイルを書き込んだり、コマンドを実行したりするために使用されます。
security because Claude can effectively search
そして基本的に、テキストを生成するだけではないすべてを行います。
your code base to find relevant code without relying
すべての言語モデルがツールを
upon indexing, which often relies upon sending
同じレベルで使用するわけではありません。
your entire code base to outside servers.
そして、これはコーディングアシスタントの全体的な効率に大きな影響を与えます。